Hello friends, my name is Abhishek Goyal
and welcome to my channel Invest Show.
Friends, today in this video we will cover the
term plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Life Insurance.  Yes friends, I am talking about
Aditya Birla's Super Term
Plan.  This is a great plan where the
company is offering multiple options.  By
adding this you can make your term plan a fully featured
term plan.  So in this video
we will cover all the features.  We will
look at their claim settlement ratio.  Will
pay their premiums.  We
will give our own opinion related to this product.
So let's cover this product in detail.   First of all
friends, here we will talk about
plan variants.  Friends, here the company
gives you three plan variants.  Level
Cover, Increase Cover, Level Cover with Return of
Premium.  We will understand these three variants
in detail.  First of all, let us talk about
their eligibility criteria.  So here
if you look at the screen, this
product can be given to all three types of genders.
Male, female, transgender.  If
I talk about the entry age, then here the
minimum entry age is 18 years and the
maximum entry age is 65 years.  If I
talk about the age of maturity, then here the
minimum age of maturity should be 28 years
and the maximum age of maturity should be 85
years.  If I talk about the premium payment term here, then the
company has given multiple options in Option One and Option Two.
Whereas for option three, the company has
given only five year, 10 year and 15 year options.  Here
you are being given the option of regular pay in all three variants.
If I talk about the policy term, then
in all three variants, the
minimum policy term should be the premium you are paying plus five years.
In case of regular payment minimum
policy term should be 10 years.  If I
talk about the maximum policy term, you can take a
maximum policy term of 55 years in all three options.
Now let's talk about
premium payment modes, here if you
want you can pay premium in all ways like yearly, half yearly, quarterly,
monthly.
But if you go monthly, quarterly or half
yearly then here the company
is charging some extra which we have given you for
reference in the screen.  If
I talk about sum insured, here the
minimum sum insured is Rs 25 and there is
no maximum limit.  Based on underwriting, the
company offers you as per your eligibility.
Let us now
understand all three variants in detail.
First of all, if you look at the screen here, the
company is giving you death benefit in level cover.
Providing terminal illness benefit.
Offering waiver of premium.  In case
of terminal illness and accidental total and
permanent disability.  At the same time,
you are also being given death benefit in increasing cover.
Terminal illness benefit is being given.  The
benefit of waiver of premium is being given.
Here the company is
also giving the option of increasing the sum insured up to 200%.
All these features are being provided in Level Cover with Return of Premium.
Accept up to 200% of sum insured
here but the company is
also giving you the benefit of return of premium on maturity.  The
death benefit payout here is
also given by the company in three ways.  The
first is Lump Sum Pay where in case of
death of the insured person, the
sum insured is given to his nominee
and the policy gets closed there itself.  The
second option here is
Monthly Income Payout where instead of lump sum
amount the company gives monthly payout.
But here the company is giving the option of monthly payout only for 10 years, 15
years or 20 years.  In the
third option, the
company is giving you the option of both.
Lumpsum plus monthly pay out.
Again, monthly payouts offer options of 10 years, 15 years, and 20
years.  Friends, you
understand all the things of all three variants one by one in detail with examples.  The
first variant is the level cover.  In this,
basically the company says that if the insured
person dies due to a natural disease or an
accident, then whatever sum
insured he has chosen and goes into
benefit payout, whether he has taken lump sum
or monthly payout, is given to his nominee
and the policy gets closed there.  Let us
consider this as an example.
Mr. Sharma, age 35 years, has
taken a One CR policy.
Whose coverage he has been taking for 85 years.
Those who have regular pay and are paying annual premium of
around ₹2,000.  Here,
he has taken the option of lump sum payout in death benefit.
Now if he dies at the age of 70, then
here he would have
paid approximately Rs 777000 premium.  So here,
as soon as death occurs,
whatever sum issue which is one CR is given to his nominee
and the policy gets closed there.
So this is how the level cover variant works.
Now let's talk about increasing cover.
So friends, here again if
any insured person dies naturally or
accidentally or through disease, then
whatever
death benefit his nominee has taken, whether it is lump sum or
income benefit, is given to him
and the policy gets closed there itself,
but friends, the
criteria for choosing the sum insured is different,
what is happening here is that as soon as he
chooses this option, his sum
insured keeps increasing by 5% every year, which
increases up to a maximum of 200% of the
base sum insured, let us understand this with an example.
For example, Mr. Patel, who is
40 years old.  Who has taken the cover of One CR
till the age of 85 years.  He has
taken limited pay instead of regular
pay where he will pay only for 15 years.
Whose annual premium is No. 935.
Here, in the death benefit, he has
taken the income option for the next 15 years.  So
here he dies at the age of 70.
Where he has paid a total premium of Rs 1493000.
Now here on death his
nominee
gets Rs 111 for the next 15 years.  After that this
policy gets closed.  So this is how the second
variant works.  Now let's talk about the
third variant, Level Cover with Return of
Premium.  So it is simple here too.   In case of the
insured person's death,
whether due to natural causes, disease or
accident, the nominee is
paid the death benefit payout, whether lump sum
or income, as per the policy
and the
policy is closed at that point.  But there is
one more thing here that if tomorrow he
survives till the policy term then he
gets survival benefit separately.  Let us
consider this as an example.  For example, Mr.
Nair, who is 40 years old.  Those who have taken once year
cover.  Cover till 8 Here
he has taken limited pay and
his annual premium is Rs 97650.  Here,
he has also taken income payout in death benefit
for 20 years.  Lump sum
benefit is also available here.  So here both of them have
taken 50-50.  Here he dies at his age.
Where he has already
paid a premium of approximately Rs 1464000.  Now
how does his nominee get the money?  So
here since they had kept 50% lumpsum payout.
So here Rs 50 lakh is given to them one time
and for the next 20 years they keep
getting Rs 20833 on monthly basis.  So this is how
this policy works.  If the person
survives till the policy term, then
whatever premium he has paid,
here he has paid approximately Rs. 1464750 premium, then the
company returns all this to him
and the policy gets closed there itself.  So
friends, this is how all these three
variants work.  Now let's talk about some benefits of this product.  The
first benefit is the terminal illness
benefit.  So this is an inbuilt benefit
in all the three variants where the company says that
if tomorrow the insured person gets a terminal
illness i.e. a life-threatening disease
and two doctors certify
that this person will not survive for more than 6 months.
So in that case the company
gives him 50% of the death benefit or once or whichever is lower here.
But there are some conditions that the terminal age should be
before 80 years and along with this the
company says that if a person becomes
terminal then tomorrow if he has
any future premium left then the
company waives off that too.
Next is the accelerated critical
illness benefit.  So here the company gives the
option of sum insured from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 50 lakh.
Where you choose any sum insured
and if tomorrow you suffer from
any disease listed in the critical analysis of the company, then the
company
pays that amount and closes the benefit of this particular rider at that very point.
We have also
provided some conditions on the screen here related to this
particular optional benefit.  Next
Stag Death Benefit.  So, if the nominee wishes,
he
can also take monthly payments instead of the lump sum death benefit over the
period of next five years.  So basically
these features are available in both the company's lump sum payout and lump sum plus income payout.
Next is enhanced live stage
protection.  So if you look at the screen here, the
company is giving you different options to increase the sum insured according to different live stages.
Here,
whatever sum insured increase there will be, the
company will not provide any kind of medical treatment.
But whenever he increases the sum insured,
he will have to pay the premium according to whatever the premium is at that time.
We have given its terms and conditions on the screen.  If you want, you can
pause the video and understand it in full detail.
Next is the early exit option.  So
here the company is also giving the option of early exit.
Where if the insured person
feels after a particular age that
he no longer needs term insurance.
So in that case, if he surrenders his policy, then the
company gives him all the money.  There
are some conditions here.  Here the company says that whenever
you exercise this early exit option.
Your age should be between 60 to 70.
This
is available only in option one and option two.  Option three
is not available to you.  Also, your
policy term should be completed for a minimum of 30 years.
And you cannot exercise
this particular feature in the last five years of the policy term end.
Also, the
maturity age of the life insured should be
70 and 70 plus.  Next is Cover
Continuous Benefit.  So, if due to some
financial constraints you are
not able to pay your premium for one year, then here the
company gives you up to 12 months time.
Where you can delay your premium for up to 12 months.
But there are some
conditions here.  First of all, your policy must
be active for the last 5 years.  Second thing,
whenever you want to exercise this feature,
you need to give a return request to the company 60 days before the policy due date or policy anniversary date.
You get this particular feature overall
three times over the entire policy term
with a gap of five years.  So
as soon as your 12 months are completed,
you have to pay both the premium of the previous year and the premium of the current year
before the grace period ends.
If you do not do this, then in that case your
policy lapses and the
company closes your policy by giving whatever paid up benefits are
there.
Next is change in premium payment term.
So here the company gives you the option to convert your regular premium
payment option into limited pay option.
But there are
some conditions here.  Here basically
you can exercise this particular feature only in option one and option two.
Basically, you can do this exercise only after the first year.
You can exercise this feature only at the time of policy anniversary.
So, all the policy holders here will have to
give a return request to the company 30 days before the policy anniversary year to get this
particular feature.  Once they change their
payment term from regular to limited,
they cannot go back to regular.
Next is Health
Management Services.  So here basically the
company is providing complimentary services
related to your diagnosis, treatment and
recovery.  Here basically the company is
providing medical consultation, coaching and
second opinion service.
All these types of
services are being provided under this
particular feature.  Next is instant
payment on claim.  So here the company says that
as soon as a person dies
and if he submits all the documents, then
with in one working the company
gives some amount of the sum insured to the nominee of that particular person.  So if
someone's sum insured is from ₹50 lakh to ₹1 crore, then the
company gives ₹1 lakh instantly.
If someone has more than ₹1 crore then it
gives ₹1 lakh.  There
are some conditions here.  The policy should be at least 3 years old.
Also, if tomorrow the
claim gets rejected due to any reason, then the
company recovers whatever amount it has given to them.  Along with this,
friends, the company has provided some riders
like Accidental Death and Disability
Rider.  So here, if you take this particular rider, then
tomorrow if you become
disabled due to an accident, then whatever
sum issue you have taken, the company gives it to you in this particular
rider.  Next is the
critical enamel rider.  So again here in
case any of the listed critical companies goes
bankrupt, then
whatever sum insured you have taken, the
company gives it to you under this particular rider.
Next is Surgical Care Rider.  So
here, if a person
is hospitalized for 24 hours due to some surgery, then
a lump sum benefit is given under this
particular rider.  Next is Hospital
Care Rider.  So again, here if a
person is admitted in the hospital for 24 hours due to some
other disease, then there also the company
provides him lump sum benefit separately.
Next is the Accidental Death Benefit
Rider.  So here, if a person
dies through an accident, then
he gets a separate benefit for the sum insured.  Next is
waiver of premium.  So, if you take this rider
and if the insured person suffers
any criticality or
disability tomorrow, then all his
future premiums get waived off.
So friends, this is how we
covered the riders.  Now let's talk about terms and
conditions.  First of all let's talk about
survival benefit.  So there is
no survival benefit of any kind in this product.
And option one, two and three.  If I
talk about maturity benefit here, then there is
no maturity benefit in Option One and Option Two.
Talking about the free look period, that is,
whenever you are taking a policy, the policy
gives you a time of up to 30 days.  Where if you do
not understand the policy and
return it to the company, your entire money is
refunded.  If I
talk about the grace period, then when the
renewal time of your policy comes, the
company again gives you 30 days from the due date.
Here you can pay your premium if you want.
If I talk about policy loan, then no
type of loan can be availed against
this policy.  If I
talk about tax benefits, then here
in the old slab, currently you are given tax benefits in ATC.
But if you go to the new slab then there is
no tax benefit there.  Now let's talk about the
company's claim settlements.  So
here the claim settlement ratio of the company from 202 to 2024 is
98.65.
Here, if I talk about the solvency ratio, then the
minimum solvency ratio should be
1.5, but here the company has maintained it very well
from the last four years, which is
approximately 1.88. If I talk about the number of claims
settled from 2024 to 25, then here the
company has
settled 6275 claims.  At the same time, the
company has rejected 80 claims.  If I
talk about percentage and reputation, then it comes out to be
1.3%.
Ideally if it stays below one it
is a little better but there is
not much here.  If I talk about death and
maturity claim amount, the
company has disbursed ₹1683
crore last year.  Here,
if I talk about the claim amount per person, then
approximately ₹27 lakh per person has been received.
Now let's talk about the premium, we have provided the
second year premium here for your reference.  The
company provides some discount in the first year.
Due to which the numbers you see
look slightly different.  So that is why the premium for the second year is
given, so that in the coming time, whatever you are paying for 5, 10
years or regular,
you will have to pay that premium there.  So
here we have the cover of Once Upon a Time by 40 Year Old Male.
Across all policies covered
till 65 age, 70 age, 75 age.  Here we have
taken limited pay i.e. 10 pay and 15 pay and also
regular pay.  So here
if you look at the screen then obviously the
premium of regular pay is less compared with
limited pay.  If I talk about discount here, then
here the company is giving 6%
discount on salad on your first year
premium.  So friends, with this we
covered all the aspects of the product.  I hope you
liked the information.  We have
provided the product brochure in the description link.
You can go further through if you want.
Now let's talk about how the product is.
Friends, definitely the product is very good.
If you ask me how is it premium wise
?  So the premium is not very low.
HDFC, ICIC, Max are all around them.
2-3000 is up and down.  What is your requirement now
?  If you are looking for a particular rider
that you are getting in it, which you are
not getting in the term plan of any other company,
then definitely you
can go for this product because here the claim
settlement of the company is also good and the
features provided are also very good.
Also friends, I would like to
tell you that whenever you take a term plan, do
your research properly.  You should
not go by just looking at the premium of a company.
Look at their claim settlement.  Look at the overall company's
service.  If you are taking a policy then
you should also see how you want to take it.  Do you want to
take it online or
offline?  If you
want to buy online, then you
prefer to buy directly from the company website or
through a broker like Policy Bazaar.
If you want to buy it offline then
again you have multiple options.
You can get it from the agent.  You
can take it through the bank, right?  You
can take it through a broker.  So here you
analyze all the things.  Only after that,
get a good term plan for yourself.  I hope
you liked my small opinion.
Friends, we deal in all major health
insurance and life insurance company
products and provide pan India
sales and service.  So
if you want to buy any product from us
then contact on the number given below.
If you have any query then
ask in the comment box.  We will try to answer your questions.  If you
like the video then please
like, share and subscribe.
Thank you.